(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention: To All Visitors
演出の都合上 照明の点滅にご注意ください
声出し応援 OK です
Please be aware of flashing lights during the show.
Vocal cheering is permitted.
BANDAI!
バンダイ、バンダイスピリッツより、
From Bandai and Bandai Spirits,
ホロライブエキスポ2025の会場にある特設ブースで、
at the special booth in the Hololive Expo 2025 venue,
展示中の新商品をチラ見せ！
here's a sneak peek at the new products on display!
新商品をご紹介！
Introducing new products!
ホロライブエキスポ2025限定の
The special Ichiban Kuji photo booth exclusive
一番くじ特設フォトブースも展開中。
to hololive EXPO 2025 is also open.
モニターをタッチしてくじ券をめくり、
Touch the monitor to flip the lottery ticket,
出てきたデザインと一緒に撮影できます。
and take a photo with the design that appears.
グッスマ
Good Smile
The last frontier から しなやかに
Gracefully from the last frontier
捧げる歌を
A song to dedicate
胸いっぱいの
Full of emotion
旅立つ歌を
A song for the journey
フリューから「ホロライブ」プライズが
Hololive prizes from FuRyu are appearing
全国アミューズメント施設にて続々展開中！
one after another in amusement centers nationwide!
台湾旅行中、最も便利な決済サービスを提供します。
Providing the most convenient payment service during your trip to Taiwan.
新商品まもなく登場！
New products coming soon!
だったらジョイサウンドX1で歌おうぜ！
Then let's sing with JOYSOUND X1!
JOYSOUND X1 Only One
JOYSOUND X1, the only one
JOYSOUND X1 曲数ナンバーワン
JOYSOUND X1, number one song count
AIが採点 絶賛 カラオケ最高
AI scoring is amazing, karaoke is the best
本物最高
The real deal is the best
JOYSOUND EVOLUTION 見よ 曲数No.1
Witness JOYSOUND EVOLUTION, number one song count
歌いたい曲があるって最高
It's great to have the songs you want to sing
CREATORS' STAGE
#hololivefesEXPO25_DAY2
バンダイ
Bandai
バンダイ、バンダイスピリッツより、
From Bandai and Bandai Spirits,
ホロライブエキスポ2025の会場にある
at the Hololive Expo 2025 venue,
特設ブースで、展示中！
now on display at the special booth!
LIFESTYLE BANDAI の新商品をご紹介！
Introducing new products from LIFESTYLE BANDAI!
ホロライブエキスポ2025限定の
一番くじ特設フォトブースも展開中！
The Ichiban Kuji special photo booth, exclusive to
hololive EXPO 2025, is also now open!
モニターをタッチしてくじ券をめくり、
出てきたデザインと一緒に撮影できます。
Touch the monitor to flip the lottery ticket and
take a photo with the design that appears.
愛を込めて　捧げる歌を...
With all my love, this song I offer...
舞い上がれ　旅立ちの歌を
Soar high, this song of departure
スケールフィギュア化決定 星街すいせい AZKi
Scale figure adaptation decided: Hoshimachi Suisei, AZKi
フリューから『ホロライブ』プライズが
全国アミューズメント施設にて続々展開中！
Hololive prizes from FuRyu are appearing
one after another in amusement facilities nationwide!
4月からは新たにひっかけフィギュアも登場！
New Hikkake figures will also be available starting from April!
90人の hololive と HOLOSTARS タレントから
好きな一人を選ぼう！
Choose your favorite from 90 hololive
and HOLOSTARS talents!
3月8日より先行予約開始
Pre-orders start March 8th
台湾旅行中、最も便利な決済サービスを提供します。
Providing the most convenient payment service while traveling in Taiwan.
hololive 6th fes. 一カ通限定盲包 第一弾
hololive 6th fes. iPASS Limited Blind Pack Vol. 1
だったら JOYSOUND X1 で歌おうぜ！
In that case, let's sing with JOYSOUND X1!
歌いたい曲があるって最高
It's the best to have the songs you want to sing
超特大ぬいぐるみブランド どきゅーと から
商品化決定！
Merchandise decided from the
extra-large plushie brand, DOQUTE!
約100cmサイズ ぬいぐるみに！
Into approximately 100cm size plushies!
グルーヴコースター最新作に、白上フブキと...
In the latest Groove Coaster game, Shirakami Fubuki and...
...さくらみこがキャラクターボイスで参戦！
...Sakura Miko join as character voices!
人気曲や、私たちが歌う曲も楽しめる！
Enjoy popular songs and the ones we sing!
私たちがグルーヴワールドをナビゲートするよ！
We'll be your guides to the Groove World!
コラボイベント実施中！ ホロライブエキスポ コナミ
Collaboration events currently underway! hololive EXPO KONAMI
ゲームのオアシスに飛び込め！
Dive into the gaming oasis!
PalVerse フィギュア化決定！！
PalVerse figure adaptation decided!!
白上フブキ・大神ミオ フィギュア化決定
3月8日(土) 予約開始！！
Shirakami Fubuki & Ookami Mio figure adaptation decided.
Pre-orders start Saturday, March 8th!!
宝鐘マリン 1/7スケールフィギュア 締切間近
Houshou Marine 1/7 scale figure deadline approaching
推しの夢叶えます。 明利酒類
Fulfilling your oshi's dreams. Meiri Shurui
2025年夏 コラボカフェ・プライズ 開催決定
Collaboration cafe and prizes decided for Summer 2025
hololive 6th fes. 応援メッセージボード
hololive 6th fes. Support Message Board
【#hololivefesEXPO25_DAY2】開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
[#hololivefesEXPO25_DAY2] Please wait a moment until the performance begins.
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention For Visitors
演出の都合上 照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援OKです
Cheering loudly is OK.
hololive 6th fes. Color Rise Harmony PENLIGHT COLORS
Color Rise Harmony
hololive 6th fes.
CREATORS: かめりあ, Giga, KIRA, ZSunder, しん, すりぃ, 梨本うい, TeddyLoid, ナユタン星人, niki, ピノキオピー, ぽるし, 柊マグネタイト, ろくろ (OSSYS)
CREATORS: Camellia, Giga, KIRA, ZSunder, Shin, Surii, Ui Nashimoto, TeddyLoid, Nayutalien, niki, PinocchioP, Polche, Hiiragi Magnetite, Rokuro (OSSYS)
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
演出の都合上 照明の点滅にご注意ください
声出し応援 OK です
Attention: To all visitors.
Due to production reasons, please be aware of flashing lights.
Vocal cheering is OK.
Attention For Visitors
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
Cheering loudly is OK.
hololive 6th fes. Color Rise Harmony
PENLIGHT COLORS
Color Rise Harmony
ハコス・ベールズ
Hakos Baelz
一味
Ichimi
WATAME FUJI!!
みコ言葉
Miko-kotoba
hololive 6th fes. DAY2
CREATORS' STAGE
hololive 6th fes. Color Rise Harmony CREATORS' STAGE
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Pallet, pallet, pallet, we will shine!
呼び合う声を合図に
With our calling voices as the signal
パレパレパレ 探しに行く
Pallet, pallet, pallet, we're going to search
スタートは何度だって
Any moment can be a start
独り言 綴った
I wrote down my soliloquies
ただ 始まりたくて走った
I ran, simply wanting to begin
遠く 暗がりと思った
I thought it was a distant darkness
それは 眩しすぎた名前
But it was a name that shone too brightly
それは 優しすぎる思い出
Those are memories that are too kind
もっと 近づけて手を伸ばした
I reached out to get closer
想いだけで結び合った
We were bound together by feelings alone
ほら 今 虹のつま先になった
Look, now we've become the tips of the rainbow
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Pallet, pallet, pallet, we will shine!
悔しさも 愛しさも 全て連れておいで
Bring your regrets, your love, and everything else with you
架せる夢 羽 飛び立たせるさ
We'll make our dreams and wings take flight
細やかな祈りは光 終わりなき兆し
Our tiny prayers are light, an endless sign
君を 見つけたこと
Finding you...
胸を張れるよ
...is something I can be proud of
ここから これから あまねく
From here, from now, everywhere...
パレパレ
Pallet, pallet!
照らしたビジョンは 君と歩くことさ
The vision that's illuminated is walking with you.
君と歩くことなんだ
It's all about walking with you.
「ただいま」を聞けば
When I hear "I'm home,"
「おかえり」って叫ぶよ
I'll shout back, "Welcome home!"
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't that just natural?
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Palette, palette, palette, it's glowing.
暗がりを満たすのは 君と僕だ
The ones filling the darkness are you and me.
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Palette, palette, palette, it's glowing.
悔しさも愛おしさも 全部おいで
The frustration and the affection, let it all come.
風 夢 羽 伸び通せるさ
Wind, dreams, wings, we can stretch them out.
鮮やかな今 祝いたい 終わりなき兆し
I want to celebrate this vivid moment, an endless sign.
君と飛び込んでゆく 素敵な「今」こそ
Diving in with you, this wonderful "now" is it.
ここから これから
From here, from now on.
Afterlight パレパレ
Afterlight, palette, palette.
どっちが好きなのよ？
Which one do you like?
CREATORS' STAGE！みんな！
CREATORS' STAGE! Everyone!
行くよー！
Here we go!
ぶち上げろー！
Let's pump it up!
なんとかなんないかな？ ラブラビ
Can't we do something about this? Love-Rabbit.
隣のアイツが邪魔だな
The person next to me is in the way.
ヤバいな こんなことダメダメ
This is bad, this kind of thing is no-no.
プランで必勝 停滞
Victory with a plan, stagnation.
どわどわ違うな なんたって競争
Dwa-dwa, that's not right, after all it's a competition.
苦手なの言うな
Don't say you're not good at it.
だんだん楽しく いともしわとしもし
Gradually getting fun, itomoshi-watoshimoshi.
あの子に負けてない ってわかっててジェラシー
Knowing I'm not losing to her, yet feeling jealous.
欲張りめ？ 横取りか？ 殺してやります あー！
Greedy? Stealing it away? I'll kill you, ah!
言わなきゃ ってわかってる
I know I have to say it.
合ってもない 吐いてもない
Not matching, not spitting it out.
止めてみましょう
Let's try to stop it.
つらぬけ My My My My
Pierce through, My My My My.
聞きたくない言い訳バニ
Don't want to hear it, Excuse-Bunny.
地団駄のYouTube だんだん
Stamping on YouTube, gradually.
ハニバニバリバリマジな話どっち
Honey-Bunny, crunch-crunch, seriously, which one?
どっちが好きなのよ
Which one do you like?
よそ見しないで
Don't look away.
逃げ出したいのは 私の方
The one who wants to run away is me.
どうしまして 反対交互
You're welcome, reverse-alternate.
ワンテン差言い訳バル
One-tempo difference, Excuse-Bar.
あなたたちー！先輩ー！
Hey you guys! Seniors!
ぺこら来てるぺこー！
Pekora is here-peko!
せーの！ぺこらキッチン！
One, two! Pekora Kitchen!
大都会も 滞留区域？
Even the big city is a stagnation zone?
興味ねぇから 超苦手
I'm not interested, so I'm super bad at it.
一網打尽 君探すハリハリ 届け機密
Rounding them up, searching for you, hurry-hurry, deliver the secret.
下等 知らぬ間 捕らえてバイビー
Inferior, caught before knowing it, bye-bye.
ドンドン 遠慮なく 食べキャロット 倍のとこ
More and more, don't hold back, eat carrots, double amount.
前進 あるのみ 空振ってエナジー
Only moving forward, missing yet energetic.
清楚で 幕張り やっちまいなさい
Seiso at Makuhari, just go for it.
疲れちゃった ひとやすみ
I'm tired, let's take a break.
なんとかね やってよね
Somehow, please handle it.
明日の私 任せろ
Tomorrow's me, count on it.
My My My My
決められない言い訳バニ
Indecisive, Excuse-Bunny.
有耶無耶演習 いざトトトト
Vague drills, here we go, totototo.
メニメニマニマニ ご執心な話し
Many, many, money, money, a devoted story.
私を見て
Look at me.
圧倒しちゃうです
I'll overwhelm you.
どんな時でも 私一途な方
Always the one-track minded me.
毎日君が 様々
Every day you are various.
やだよ
No way
有象無象
Mishmash
喧嘩しないで
Don't fight
逃げ出したい だけどやるしかない
I want to run away, but I have no choice
さあ、四面楚歌 反対方向
Now, besieged on all sides, opposite direction
満点さ 言い訳ばかり
Perfect score, nothing but excuses
止まって 言い訳ばかり
Stop, nothing but excuses
あー、あー
Ah, ah
だっだっだ 大好きっ！ルージュ
Da-da-da, I love you! Rouge
行きますよー、せーの！
Here we go, one-two!
無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！
Innocent! Innocent! A pretty girl is innocent!
マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！
Marine! Marine! Marine is innocent!
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
Sparkling as expected, making you more dizzy
ねえ、言ったよね。年齢なんて関係ないってさ
Hey, you said it. That age doesn't matter
そういうめんどくさいのも含めて愛してくれるって
That you'd love me even with all that trouble
ねえ、ねえ、言ったよね？言ってない？
Hey, hey, you said it, right? You didn't?
ふーん、そういうこと言うんだ。
Hmph, so that's how it is.
ちなみにこの船では美少女無罪が適用されますけど
By the way, on this ship, the "pretty girl innocence" rule applies
待たせて 魔法で若返り
Making you wait, rejuvenated by magic
秘密の素顔は君にだけ
My secret face is only for you
特別ですよ
It's special
お化粧濃いよ
Your makeup is thick
見逃さないじゃん
You don't miss a thing
おしゃべりには 近寄らないね
Don't get close to the chatter
宝の島に
To the treasure island
連れてほしい！しゅっぱつ！
I want you to take me! Departure!
ヨーソロー！全員、美少女無罪！
I-I-Sir! Everyone is an innocent pretty girl!
君の一番 目指してよーそろー！
Aiming to be your number one, I-I-Sir!
本当は自信ないけど 頑張っちゃうほい！
Actually, I'm not confident, but I'll do my best!
きゅっ、きゅるん！きゅっ、きゅるん！
Kyu, kyurun! Kyu, kyurun!
恋する気持ち 17歳だ
The feeling of love, I'm seventeen
全開になっちゃうわ 大人の時間
I'm going full throttle, it's adult time
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
Sparkling as expected, making you more dizzy
ドキドキして ルージュ
My heart is racing, Rouge
まだ早い
It's still too early
だっだっだ 駄目です。フリルの服着た
Da-da-da, it's no good. Wearing frilly clothes
そんなことないよ
That's not true
だっだっだ 魔法少女になってみたい
Da-da-da, I want to try being a magical girl
ギリギリ有罪
Barely guilty
ピノ 7世 ピンクになれ最強説
Pino the 7th, become pink, the strongest theory
結局君も もっと若い子
In the end, you too like younger girls
なんでもするから 見捨てないで君たち！
I'll do anything, so don't abandon me, guys!
やっぱりどこか見てみたい
As expected, I want to see somewhere
たまにはいいじゃん それでもいいの
Sometimes it's fine, even so it's fine
お仕事だもん 本気にしちゃう？
It's just work, are you getting serious?
あるじの宝物
The master's treasure
一緒に行こう！しゅっぱつ！
Let's go together! Departure!
ハートにジャムを 美少女無罪
Jam in the heart, pretty girl innocence
ほらほら どうして？ めんどくさいの待ってるの
Come on, come on, why? A lot of trouble is waiting
ちょっと構ってくれる 君が好き！はい！
I like you, who pays a little attention to me! Yes!
きゅっ、きゅるん！きゅっ、きゅるん！
Kyu, kyurun! Kyu, kyurun!
優しくしてね 17歳
Be kind to me, I'm seventeen
ズッコンデゲンキをお楽しみ中
Enjoying being pumped up and energetic
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
Sparkling as expected, making you more dizzy
ドキドキして ルージュ
My heart is racing, Rouge
お許しください
Please forgive me
このマリンの 魅力 魔力 二人のエコー
This Marine's charm, magical power, the echo of two
全人類オンナね
All of humanity are women, right?
探さないで 捕まえて
Don't search for me, catch me
天才の色 さあ見てあげるから！しゅっぱつ！
The color of a genius, come on, I'll watch over you! Departure!
ヨーソロー！全員、美少女無罪！
I-I-Sir! Everyone is an innocent pretty girl!
君の一番 目指してよーそろー！
Aiming to be your number one, I-I-Sir!
冗談も大好きだけど 真剣よ！
I love jokes too, but I'm serious!
きゅっ、きゅるん！きゅっ、きゅるん！
Kyu, kyurun! Kyu, kyurun!
恋する気持ち 17歳だ
The feeling of love, I'm seventeen
全開になっちゃうわ 大人の時間
I'm going full throttle, it's adult time
ドキドキして ルージュ
My heart is racing, Rouge
まだ早い
It's still too early
無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！
Innocent! Innocent! A pretty girl is innocent!
マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！
Marine! Marine! Marine is innocent!
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
Sparkling as expected, making you more dizzy
マリンじゃなくて マリン絶好調！
Not Marine, Marine is in top form!
幕張、楽しんでるかい！？
Makuhari, are you having fun!?
盛り上がっていくぞ！Let's show-choo-choo!
Let's get fired up! Let's show-choo-choo!
Here we roll, say we house, say we just play dice
Baby baby there's no need to think twice Nani-nani-na oh
Make it your light make it your vibe make it your spotlight
Get off the hamster wheel and move your life
Maybe so the replacement, gang, and here we go
upon the all or win, you rip and tear
We have no time to complain
'cause I can show it can do it over again
If we can laugh it doesn't matter where or when
三、二、一、発信！
3, 2, 1, Launch!
Physics jump, play the dice, so let trouble stir and rise
Be limitless, bounce, lose the chains
意味なんて　な　な　な　ない！
There's no, no, no, no meaning!
So we don't give a jam, やんなこと　そっとミュート
So we don't give a jam, quietly mute the unpleasant things
So find something new,
軽～く宙を舞うなら　三、二、一
If you dance lightly in the air, 3, 2, 1
Bae! Bae! Bae!
Here we roll, as here we cast, as here we just play dice
Down the screen, come on out, don't be so nice
Die, die, die, die, oh! Follow your heart,
don't be so distant, come and join the club
Go and scream for you, the one who's flying free
かざすダイスを　そのままに
Keep the dice held up just as they are
For this moment, I am truly, really me
I'm about to take two, one, blast!
なんじゃかんじゃ　Ratty-rat-rat-rat
This and that, Ratty-rat-rat-rat
Now here I will recite to you the only thing that will hold true
YOLO is my ninja way and time to put the moves on display
Why stress about tomorrow when you've got today?
三、二、一、シャッフル！
3, 2, 1, Shuffle!
今が最高、最低なんて誰も知らない
Now is the best, no one knows what's the worst
人生そうせい　修正ってマジで短～い
Life creation, corrections are seriously short
What are we seeing? A jam! パッと思いついて Q！
What are we seeing? A jam! Suddenly popped into my head, Q!
So rush on to our root, 走る早さに身を任せて　Then you...
So rush on to our root, leave yourself to the speed of running, then you...
Here we roll, as here we cast, as here we just play dice
このAdventure, inside mine, don't stop it's time
This Adventure, inside mine, don't stop it's time
Die, die, die, die, oh! Come and run and follow us,
don't stop 'til we're done
Idiot, throw it out, infinite bye!
みんな自由じゃなきゃもったいないじゃん
It's a waste if everyone isn't free
It's not too late, our journey's just begun!
I'm about to take two, one, blast!
That's a game over, you are screwed!
泣いても笑っても　チュ、チュ、チュ！
Whether you cry or laugh, chu chu chu!
Baby, baby, it's time to... die!
チュ、チュ、チュ！
Chu chu chu!
Here we roll, as here we cast, as here we just play dice
Baby, baby, I was leaning into ninja style
Die, die, die, die, oh! This is our life,
this is our vibe, this is our spotlight
Before giving in, go show them your best try!
崩壊社会から　もう、生ききれな～い
Can't live through this collapsing society anymore
What you doing, Rat? Go around and live your life!
I'm about to take two, one, blast!
Dice, dice, throw it down! Blast!
Blah, blah, blah, blah, なんじゃかんじゃ
Blah, blah, blah, blah, this and that
Blah, blah, blah, blah, Ratty-rat-rat-rat
Blah, blah, blah, blah, なんじゃかんじゃ
Blah, blah, blah, blah, this and that
Blah, blah, blah, blah!
つまんないです　嘘なんて　奇跡願ってる時の人生
Lies are boring, life when wishing for a miracle
Watch me, get to the 充実　ひしひしと取り戻す君のマジック
Watch me, get to fulfillment, keenly taking back your magic
Want to be free 誰だって free　ダッシュ、バッシュ、もっとステップ
Want to be free, everyone's free, dash, bash, more steps
ヘイタクシー！ちょっと宇宙まで
Hey taxi! Just to outer space
秒針は音を立てて　容赦急かす魔物のように
The second hand makes a sound, like a monster rushing without mercy
人生を一瞬にして　解ける魔法
Turning life into a moment, a magic that dissolves
それならば駆け抜けて　もう一度に
If so, run through it, once more
おしゃまなおしゃべり乗せて　サバイビー
With precocious chatter, survive-y
私は大変身メーカー　我が儘の間に間に
I'm a great transformation maker, between selfishness
煌めきにチュチュチュ
A chu chu chu to the sparkle
回してダンシング　サヨナラ・グッバイ・エンドレス
Spinning and dancing, sayonara, goodbye, endless
いつかは喝采食らうつもりよ　みなみなご愁傷様
Someday I intend to receive applause, my condolences to everyone
怖がってもしょうがないから
There's no use being afraid,
終端を飛び出せ
so jump out from the end
今夜に出会ったのならば　自由で満月、でしょう？
If we met tonight, it's a free full moon, right?
タ、タ、ダンス！　な、な、な、な、法
Da, da, dance! La, la, la, la, law
どんな問題も会話ひとつ　白紙も正解
Any problem solved with one conversation, even a blank sheet is correct
間違いも愛す 本当の私の理想？
I love even my mistakes, my true ideal?
あぁなんだか世界は 限界の気配がして
穏やかな安心と心配が
Ah, somehow the world feels like it's at its limit,
With calm peace and worry mixed together.
今すぐ Jumping, jumping now
Jumping, jumping now!
チキチキバンバン チキバンバン
威風堂々 危機怪々
Chiki chiki ban ban, chiki ban ban,
Majestic and bizarre crisis.
日々ギリギリ爆発 君たった今
発射してしまおうか
Exploding every day at the edge,
Shall we launch you right now?
まだまだビリビリ段々 軽微に願望
一発じゃ物足りないわ
Still tingling bit by bit, minor desires,
A single shot is just not enough.
遂に導き出した 君にアンサー
灰になれるまで踊っていよう
Finally found the answer for you,
Let's dance until we turn to ash.
やあ、楽しかったな！みんなのビビデバ！
Man, that was fun! Everyone's 'Bibi-de-ba'!
熱い熱い！熱かったね！
So hot, so hot! That was intense!
遊ばせていただきました！
みんな踊ってくれてありがとう！
We had a blast! Thank you all for dancing with us!
イェイイェイイェーイ！
Yay, yay, yay!
ではね、はい、自己紹介をさせていただこうかなと。
Well then, I think it's time for some self-introductions.
こちらから順番にお願いします。
Let's go in order, starting from this side.
あ、そちらから。そらから！
Oh, starting there? Then Sora's first!
えっと、みんな「こんそめ」って言ったら
「ぬんぬん」って返してください。
Um, everyone, when I say 'Consome',
please reply with 'Nun nun'.
こんにちは、ときのそらです。こんそめーーー！
Hello, I'm Tokino Sora. Consome---!
ぬんぬんーーー！
Nun nun---!
ありがとう！ぬんぬんぬんぬん...
Thank you! Nun nun nun nun...
はい！ではAZKiも
コール＆レスポンスやりたいと思います！
Alright! AZKi would like to do
a call and response too!
はい！いつものね、自己紹介を言ったら...
Okay! After I do my usual self-introduction...
みんな「AZKiのハートを」って言ったら
「ゼロゲイザー」でお願いします！
When I say 'To AZKi's heart',
please respond with 'Zero Gazer'!
はい！ではいきますよ！
右手にマイク、左手に地図。AZKiのハートをーーー？
Alright! Here we go!
Mic in my right hand, map in my left. To AZKi's heart---?
ゼロゲイザーーーー！
Zero Gazer----!
ありがとう！イェッサ！イェッサ！みんなありがとう！
Thank you! Yes, sir! Yes, sir! Thank you everyone!
ではすいちゃん！
Your turn, Sui-chan!
はい！もうすいちゃんはみんなわかってるよね？
もう言わないからね！
Alright! Everyone already knows Sui-chan, right?
I won't even say it!
すいちゃんいきますよ！彗星の如く現れたスターの原石！
バーチャルアイドルの星街すいせいです！
Sui-chan's coming through! A rough diamond that appeared like a comet!
I'm the virtual idol Hoshimachi Suisei!
すいちゃんはーーー？
Sui-chan is---?
今日もかわいい！ばっちり！ばっちり！
Cute today too! Perfect! Perfect!
ありがとう！なんか聞こえる...何も聞こえない。
ありがとう！はいどうぞ！
Thank you! I hear something... No, I hear nothing.
Thank you! Next, please!
はい！ロボ子もコール＆レスポンスやりたい！
Yes! Roboco wants to do a call and response too!
ロボ子はもちろん、えー「高性能」って
言ってくれますよね？
Roboco, of course, um, you'll call me
'High-Performance', right?
高性能？言えるかな？
High-Performance? Can you say it?
言えるよーーー！
We can say it---!
言えるかな？えりおなみごっち...
Can you? Erionamigocchi...
ぽぽぽ...信じてるからね！高性能！
Po po po... I'm counting on you! High-Performance!
はい、いきます！はい！ロボ子さーーーんわーーー？
Alright, here we go! Okay! Roboco-san is---?
高性能ーーー！
High-Performance---!
一番近いところから違うのが聞こえる...
そういうことだよ。
I hear something different from the closest spot...
So that's how it is.
しょうがない。ロボ子間違えちゃった。
Oh well. Roboco made a mistake.
くっそー...仕方ねえな。だにごっち。はいどうぞ！
Damn... can't be helped then. Danigocchi. Next, please!
えーじゃあ、みこがみこちゃんはーって言ったら、
もうみんなわかるよね？
Well then, when Miko says 'Miko-chan is-',
everyone already knows, right?
エリートだよね？
It's 'Elite', right?
ん？何今の間...だいじょうぶかな？
みこぴーだいじょうぶだよね？
Huh? What was that pause... Is she okay?
Mikopi's doing fine, right?
じゃあいきますよ！にゃっはろーーー！
Alright, here we go! Nyahallo---!
にゃっはろーーー！
Nyahallo---!
エリートみこアイドルのさくらみこです。みこちゃんはーーー？
I'm the Elite Miko idol, Sakura Miko. Miko-chan is---?
エリートーーーー！
Elite----!
エリートだ！ありがとう！よかったよかった。
Elite indeed! Thank you! Thank goodness.
ということでクリエイターズステージ始まりましたけど...
And so, the Creators' Stage has begun...
0期生が集まって！わーい！サビから！サビでパーンって出る！
Generation 0 gathered together! Yay! From the chorus!
It pops out at the chorus!
やったー！ お疲れ様ー！
We did it! Good job!
へへ、頑張りました。
Hehe, I did my best.
いやもう最初からかっ飛ばしてるセトリでしたけれども。
The setlist was going full throttle from the start.
そうですね！ 本当に！
That's right! Really!
なんかすごい「よかったよかった」って、ここら辺にコメントも見えてます。
I can see comments saying "It was good, it was good" around here.
コメントも見えてますね、ありがとう！
I see the comments too, thank you!
ありがとうー！ エリートー！
Thank you! Elite!
配信もありがとう！ ありがとうねー！
Thanks for watching the stream too! Thank you!
ということで、えっと、ハッシュタグは、
And so, the hashtag is...
ホロライブフェスエキスポ25...
#hololivefesEXPO25...
アンダーバーデイツー！
_DAY2!
で、たくさんポストしてください！
Please post a lot using it!
ポストして！ 目指せトレンド入り！ よろしくお願いしまーす！
Please post! Let's get it trending! Thank you!
でさ、みんなでやりたいことが...
And now, there's something I want to do with everyone.
あ、そうだ、やりたいこと話し合ってたじゃん！ やりたいことある！
Oh, right! We were talking about what we wanted to do! We have something!
決めましたよね！ じゃあ、ここは説明がうまいAZKiさん！
We decided, didn't we? Then, AZKi-san, you're good at explaining!
え、ここ説明がうまいAZKiさんお願いします！
Wait, "good at explaining AZKi-san", please!
本日は0期生が集まったということで、みんなにペンライトで協力してほしいことがあります！
Since all the 0th gen members are here today, there's something we want you to help us with using your penlights!
今からちょっと立ち位置を変えますので...
We're going to change our positions slightly now...
みんなの目の前にいる、あの0期生のメンバーカラーにペンライトを変えてください！
Please change your penlight to the color of the 0th gen member right in front of you!
これでだいたい、これでだいたいみんなわかるかな？
With this, I wonder if everyone will understand.
だいたいわかるかな？ いけるかな？
They'll probably understand, right? Can we do it?
みんな、今自分の目の前にいるホロメンのカラーにペンライト変えてみて！
Everyone, try changing your penlight color to the color of the holomem in front of you!
いや、君たちできるじゃない！
Hey, you guys can do it!
すごーい！ 上手ー！ やるね！
Amazing! So good! You did it!
すごい！ 難しいと思ってたのに！
Incredible! I thought it would be difficult!
そうそう！ めっちゃきれいに分かれてる！
Yeah! It's divided so clearly!
でさ、じゃあちょっと、どのチームが一番声がでかいか...
So, let's see which team has the loudest voice!
ここで0期生バトルが始まってしまう！ おまえら頑張れよ！
The 0th gen battle has started here! Good luck, everyone!
頑張れよー！ 負けねーぞ！ 頑張れよー！
Good luck! I won't lose! Good luck!
じゃあ、どのチームからいきます？ どこからいくの？
Then, which team should we start with? Where from?
じゃあロボ子さん。 ほい、勝負！ じゃあロボちからいきましょう！
How about Roboco-san? Okay, it's a fight! Let's start with Robochi!
じゃあみんな、声一発目から出せるよね！？
Then, everyone! You can shout from the very first one, right?!
めっちゃ声出てるじゃん！ すごい！
Your voices are so loud! Amazing!
すごーい！ いいよ！ ロボ子さんチーム！
Amazing! That's good! Roboco-san's team!
じゃあ次すいちゃんチームね！ 分かってるよね？
Then, next is Sui-chan's team! You know what to do, right?
あ、これやばいぞ！ よろしく頼むぜ！
Oh, this is going to be big! I'm counting on you!
じゃあ、いくよ！ すいちゃんはー！？
Okay, here we go! Sui-chan wa—!?
素晴らしい！ 声がでかい！
Wonderful! So loud!
じゃあエリートじゃないやつにしてみようかな？ 何だ何だ？
Then, how about something other than "Elite"? What is it?
みこおで、って言ったら「誇らしいよ」って言ってもらおうかな？
When I say "Miko Ode", I want you to say "Hokorashi-yo"!
はずか... 違うでしょ！ 「みこ誇らしい」って最近言い過ぎてますから！
Embarras... No! It's because I've been saying "Miko is proud" too much lately!
はずこ、はずこ。 いくよ、みんな。 えっと、何だっけ？
Embarrassing. Ready everyone? Um, what was it?
忘れた！？ みこおでね、いくよ！
You forgot?! Miko Ode, right? Here we go!
みこおでー！
Miko Ode—!
ありがとう！ 出てる出てる！ やったやった！
Thank you! It came out! Yay!
みんな頑張れるよね？ そしたらー！
Everyone can do their best, right? Then—!
あ、ありがとうー！ イエーイ！
Oh, thank you! Yay!
私がさっきコンソメって言ったけど、今度はみんなにコンソメって言ってもらおうかな？
I said "Consome" earlier, so this time I want everyone to say "Consome"!
いいね！ いけるよね！ 私がコンソメって言ったらコンソメって返してください！
Nice! You can do it! When I say "Consome", please reply with "Consome"!
みんな！ コンソメー！
Everyone! Consome—!
すごーい！ いい声！ 素晴らしい！
Amazing! Great voices! Wonderful!
最後！ 最後ですからね、みんな、ちゃんと声出してくださいね！
Last one! It's the last one, everyone, please give it your all!
今日は皆さんどこに来ましたか？ 幕張メッセですよね！？
Where did everyone come today? It's Makuhari Messe, right?!
みんな、幕張メッセを「ゲース」でお願いします！ 幕張メッセをー！
Everyone, give me a "Geesu" for Makuhari Messe! Makuhari Messe o—!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
みんな声がデカくなったね
Everyone's voice got louder.
みんな声が出てたね
Everyone was really letting their voices out.
勝者はいない、引き分け
There's no winner, it's a draw.
仲良しだ
We're such good friends.
戻りましょう
Let's head back.
はい、ということで皆様に悲しいお知らせがあります
Alright, so I have a sad announcement for everyone.
無料パートはここまで！
The free part ends here!
そこの貴方たち、まだチケットを買っていないの？
You guys over there, haven't you bought your tickets yet?
早く今から買って！
Go buy them right now, hurry!
この後も見たいでしょ？
You want to keep watching, don't you?
よろしくね！
Please look forward to it!
飛んでみろ！
Try jumping!
Jump, jump!
出るだろう、チャリンチャリン鳴るだろう！
It'll come out! You'll hear the 'clink-clink'!
最後のコメントで締めたいと思います
I'd like to close with a final comment.
みんな分かっている、あの言葉！
Everyone knows it, that phrase!
会場のみんなも一緒に言ってくださいね
Everyone at the venue, please say it with us.
ポーズは適当で
Just do whatever pose.
ポーズは適当で、オッケーオッケー
A random pose, okay okay.
あのポーズね、オッケー
That pose, right? Got it.
行くよ、せーの！
Ready? One, two!
Color Rise Harmony!
無料パートは終了いたしました！ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The free part of the show has ended. Thank you for watching.
無料パートは終了いたしました！
The sneak peek part of the show has ended.
ご視聴ありがとうございました！
Thank you for watching.